<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>marriage &#8211; Ds Sinonjs</title>
	<atom:link href="https://ds.sinonjs.org/tag/marriage/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://ds.sinonjs.org</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 09:46:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Women in the Philippines want the right to divorce</title>
		<link>https://ds.sinonjs.org/2023/06/01/women-in-the-philippines-want-the-right-to-divorce/</link>
					<comments>https://ds.sinonjs.org/2023/06/01/women-in-the-philippines-want-the-right-to-divorce/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tetreamra]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 09:46:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philippines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[woman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ds.sinonjs.org/?p=5</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Stella Sibonga, a mother of three from the Philippines, wants a divorce. But he can&#8217;t [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Stella Sibonga, a mother of three from the Philippines, wants a divorce. But he can&#8217;t because of the laws of the Catholic majority country. Divorce is illegal in this country. The Philippines is the only place outside the Vatican where divorce is prohibited. And it takes years to resolve the matter in court.</p>



<p>Divorce lawyers argue that the ban makes it harder for couples to break up and remarry. Surviving a violent relationship is very difficult for them.</p>



<p>The legal process in this regard is very slow and expensive in the country. Such a case in this impoverished country can cost upwards of $10,000. However, there is no guarantee of success. This is why some people are getting involved in online scams for quick results.</p>



<p>Stella Sibonga, 45, a resident of Manila, has been trying to get a divorce for 11 years. He said, &#8216;I don&#8217;t understand why it has to be so difficult.&#8217; Stella&#8217;s legal battle began in 2012. Then she applied to the court for divorce alleging &#8216;mental disability&#8217; against her husband.</p>



<p>After paying $3,500 in legal fees over five years, a judge ruled in his favor. Stella was somewhat relieved by this. But that relief was short-lived. Because the Solicitor General&#8217;s Office, which is responsible for protecting the institution of marriage in the country, appealed against this decision in 2019. That appeal is still pending.</p>



<p>Stella said she later appealed to the Court of Appeal to have the verdict reversed. The court has not given any decision on this yet. He further said, &#8216;We who are suffering, have faced abuse, why are we being punished by the law? We want to be free.&#8217;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">void marriage</h2>



<p>The strongest opponent of divorce in the Philippines is the Catholic Church. The organization is also vocal against abortion and contraception.</p>



<p>About 78 percent of the country&#8217;s 1.1 million people are Catholic, according to official census data. For this reason, many politicians are wary of opposing the Church on sensitive social issues.</p>



<p>But in recent years, the Congress has made significant gains in these respects. A controversial birth control law was passed in 2012 despite strong opposition from the Church. In 2018, a majority of members of the House of Representatives and opposition parties approved the divorce bill, which was later stalled in the Senate. This is the first time that such a proposal has been made so far.</p>



<p>According to a survey conducted by social weather station, the attitude of Filipino citizens towards divorce is changing. In 2005, 43 percent of citizens who did not want to live together supported the legalization of divorce. And 45 percent of citizens disagreed. In the same survey in 2017, 53 percent showed support, while only 32 percent disagreed.</p>



<p>A group of lawmakers are currently pushing several bills in the House and Senate to legalize divorce.</p>



<p>&#8220;We don&#8217;t want to destroy any marriage,&#8221; said Edsel Lagman, a member of Congress and author of one of the bills. He also said, &#8216;A dysfunctional marriage is beyond reformation.&#8217; If it is legalized, victimized women and their children will be saved from &#8216;intolerant and oppressive husbands&#8217;. However, he also commented that &#8216;quick divorce&#8217; will not be allowed.</p>



<p>Before being elected, the country&#8217;s president, Ferdinand Marcos, said the country should consider allowing divorce. However, he insisted, the matter should not be too easy.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Online scams</h2>



<p>The process of obtaining a court order for divorce is very complex. Underneath this complexity, online scams have emerged. Through this, a cycle offers to ensure quick judgment without appearing in court.</p>



<p>AFP&#8217;s fact checker found numerous Facebook posts spreading false information about the legal process of divorce to attract clients. Such fraudsters are profiting financially by giving false information.</p>



<p>One victim told AFP he was charged US$2,400 for a service that later turned out to be bogus. The woman is now considering converting to Islam in hopes of getting a divorce under Muslim law.</p>



<p>The woman said on condition of anonymity, &#8216;I am trying all possible options to be alone again. Divorce takes a long time, is very expensive—yet there are no guarantees. So I&#8217;m looking for an easier way.&#8217;</p>



<p>Family law expert Katrina Legarda said the number of people behind the fake service proved that a new law was &#8216;much needed&#8217;.</p>



<p>But Father Jerome Cecilano of the Catholic Bishops&#8217; Conference of the Philippines said the nation should be &#8220;proud&#8221; of being the only country outside the Vatican to &#8220;retain the traditional concept of marriage&#8221;. Father said, there will always be imperfections in a relationship. She also said that divorcing an abusive partner would &#8216;perpetuate the violence&#8217;. Because, the offender will also oppress their next partner.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Stella is scared</h2>



<p>Stella Sibonga is herself a Catholic. However, fearing that he might be accused of adultery, he stopped going to church.</p>



<p>Stella has been in love for a long time. But he is not able to tie the knot with that lover until the legal separation of the first marriage. Small cases in the Philippines take years to go to trial. No wonder it&#8217;s taking so long for Stella&#8217;s divorce case to end there.</p>



<p>Stella says, &#8216;I&#8217;m still technically married. Because of this, people think that I am a sinner. They believe that those whom God has brought together cannot be separated. Really? Even if your husband tries to kill you, divorce is not allowed?&#8217;</p>



<p>Stella also said that her relationship with her husband is not very good. Her husband forced her to commit suicide twice. Stella does not want her children to get married before her divorce. He said, &#8216;I told the children that they can have as many children as they want without marriage. But I will never agree to their marriage. I don&#8217;t want their lives to end like mine.&#8217;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://ds.sinonjs.org/2023/06/01/women-in-the-philippines-want-the-right-to-divorce/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
